MICHAEL ADENUGBA

Software Engineer | Web Developer Frontend | Backend | Web Design UI/UX | Open-Source Contributor GitHub | Twitter | My Website E: adenughamicke@gmail.com
No 65, Redemption Way, Off
Sabo RD, Ondo, Nigeria
LinkedIn Profile®

T: (+234) 705-186-0871

SUMMARY

A **software engineer** with 2 years of experience in front-end, and database development. A personable, communicative, UI/UX-oriented developer who specializes in web applications and things people will like to use. I also use an open source to share knowledge.

SKILLS

Language: HTML, CSS, JS, English(native)
Frameworks: ReactJS, NextJS, Typescript
Library: NodeJS, Chakra UI, Tailwind CSS.
Tools: VsCode, Git, Github, Js Snippets, Figma.

Host: Netlify, Github, Vercel, Wordpress

Hobbies: Playing Chess, Podcast

Database: Firebase, GraphQL mongoDb
Open source: Github, Netlify, Stackoverflow
Test Environment: Postman, Codespen
Dev Community: Hashnode, Twitter, Gist
Payment API: Stripe, Paypal, Paystack
References: Available on demand

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Project Management-app

JULY 2022

A simple app created to manage clients and projects, built with React, GraphQL/Apollo and RESTful API.

Hotel-app

JUNE 2022

A booking app marketplace. Code base uses RESTful API, React, MongoDb, Agolia, Jwt, Express and Stripe API.

Loaff-app

MAY 2022

Fully optimized responsive food service website, built with HTML, Javascript and CSS.

Foodshop

MARCH 2022

An ecommerce platform for online food-store with payment integration, built with React, RESTful API, MongoDb, Express-jwt and Paypal API.

My Portfolio

Set for completion in OCTOBER 2022. A service rendering portfolio website with advanced features like blog, SEO. Code base uses NextJS, Firebase, AuthO, MongoDb, Express-Jwt and RESTful API.

Kia Clothing

Set for completion in OCTOBER 2022.
An ecommerce app for online grocery purchase with payment integration. Code base uses React, Firebase, RESTful API, GraphQL/Apollo.

MeetupCamp

Set for completion in NOVEMBER 2022. An application developed to give info on future meetups/events. Code base uses NodeJS, RESTful API, EJS, MongoDb and Express.

My Ecommerce Book

Set for completion in November 2022.

A fully-fledge app created to store book items for purchase. Code base uses NextJS,
GraphQL/Apollo, Snipcart and Wordpress.

My Posts-app

APRIL 2022

A single static page for post built with NextJS, Storybook, Applitools and Airtable.

UI Components

MARCH 2021

Created different brand logo, UI forms, multicolor palette typefaces with figma.

Pac-Man

SETEMBER 2022

One player game built with HTML, CSS and Javascript.

EXPERIENCE

Syarpa, Nigeria/USA — Frontend. AUGUST 2022 — PRESENT

Thinking through the user interface, contributing and advocating for new features and products support.

Fashion flair(FF), UK — Fashion flair Virtual Assistance.

MARCH 2020 — SEPTEMBER 2021 Help to manage, process and update products with new items for online purchase. **Storydium,** Nigeria — Frontend.

MARCH 2020 — JUNE 2020

Contributing and supporting the project. Help to

Design of fiber-optic network in South Eastern part of Nigeria — Network Project.

JUNE 2016 - AUGUST 2016

plan user interface.

Basemap acquisition, network analysis, spatial analysis of routes, adjoining points of cable and production of digital map for coverage extent of fiber optic project.

EDUCATION

Colt Steele — Udemy, Online.

JUNE 2022 — JUNE 2022

JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures

Zuri Training, Ingressive Fund — Slack/Youtube, Online.

MARCH 2021 — AUGUST 2021
Frontend Development

Federal University of Technology, Akure, Nigeria.

JUNE 2012 — MARCH 2018

Bachelor of Engineering in Electrical and Electronics Engineering {B.Engr.)

Gateway ICT Polytechnic, Ewekoro, Ogun State, Nigeria. MARCH 2009 — SEPTEMBER 2011 National Diploma in Electrical and Electronics.